A Guide to the J. Hoge Tyler Family Collection, 1802-1956
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- SERIES XIII: PHOTOGRAPHS 1890-1939
  - Lily Tyler Wilson family
    - J. Hoge Tyler Wilson (Box-folder 80-8)
      - J. Hoge Tyler Wilson [photo 040] 1931
        J. Hoge Tyler Wilson [040]
      - In officer's uniform [photos 041-042] n.d.
        J. Hoge Tyler Wilson [041]
        J. Hoge Tyler Wilson [042]
      - [J. Hoge Tyler Wilson] studio portrait [photo 043] n.d., [2 copies]
        J. Hoge Tyler Wilson [043]
    - Wilson family portraits (Box-folder 80-9)
      - Henry J. and Calvin Wilson daguerreotype (reproduction) [photo 044] n.d., [2 copies]
      - Henry H. Wilson family Christmas portrait [photo 045] n.d.
        Henry H. Wilson Family [045]
      - Studio portrait of Henry and Lily Wilson's children [photo 046] n.d.
        Henry H. Wilson Family [046]
      - Studio portrait of [J. Tyler Wilson and Lily Norwood Wilson] [photos 047-048] n.d.
        J. Tyler Wilson and Lily Norwood Wilson [048]
      - Studio portraits of Henry H. Wilson family [photos 049-051] n.d.
        Henry H. Wilson Family [050]
    - Lily Tyler Wilson studio portraits (Box-folder 80-10)
      - Wearing "Let George Do It" banner, with unidentified man and woman [photo 052] n.d.
      - As teenager [photos 053-054] n.d.
        Lily Tyler Wilson [053]
      - [Lily Tyler Wilson] [photo 055] n.d., [2 copies]
        Lily Tyler Wilson [055]
    - Wilson family snapshots (Box-folder 80-11)
      - Lily Tyler, Constance Mitchell, Daisy Gabbert, Cary Preston and Fanny Urquhart [photo 056] n.d.
      - [Lily Tyler Wilson] with others on mountaintop [photos 057-058] n.d.
      - [Henry and Lily Tyler Wilson] with horse and carriage [photos 059-062] n.d.
      - [Wilson children] with other unidentified children [photos 063-073] n.d.
        Henry H. Wilson Family [069]
      - [Wilson family] at Carter H. Harrison's home (Powhatan Co., Virginia) [photo 074] n.d.
      - Henry H. Wilson [photo 075] n.d.
      - [Lily Tyler Wilson] (center) with unidentified others [photo 076] n.d.
        Lily Tyler Wilson [076]
      - [Lily Tyler Wilson] driving car at Daytona Beach, Florida [photo 077]
      - [Wilson family and friends] on residential sidewalk [photos 078-084] n.d.
    - Lily Norwood Wilson (Box-folder 81-1)
      - Seiler School Primary Department [photo 085] 1927
      - Seiler School Hockey Team (Lily N. Wilson at far left) [photo 086] 1929
      - Studio portrait [photo 087] 1931
        Lily Norwood Wilson [087]
      - Studio portrait [photo 088] 1933, [2 copies]
        Lily Norwood Wilson [088]
      - Studio portrait [photo 089] 1935, [2 copies]
      - Studio portraits [photos 090-092] 1936, n.d.
        Lily Norwood Wilson [090]
        Lily Norwood Wilson [091]
        Lily Norwood Wilson [092]
      - Studio portraits [photos 093-095] n.d., [2 copies of each]
      - Unidentified group of girls (Lily N. Wilson believed to be in second row, third from left) [photo 096] n.d.
    - Henry H. Wilson Jr. (Box-folder 81-2)
      - Studio portrait [photo 097] 1931
        Henry H. Wilson, Jr. [097a]
        Henry H. Wilson, Jr. [097b]
      - Studio portrait [photo 098] 1939, [2 copies]
        Henry H. Wilson, Jr. [098]
  - Identified portraits, A-B (Box-folder 81-3)
    - George A. Alexander [photo 099]
    - Dr. J. H. C. Bagby [photo 100] [1893]
    - John Macky Baldwin [photo 101] 1895
    - Mary Belle Baskinville [photo 102] n.d.
    - Dr. W. Blain [photo 103] [1893]
    - Elizabeth Gay Bolling (photos of paintings) [photos 104-105] n.d.
    - Jno. Bolling Jr. (photo of painting) [photo 106] n.d.
    - Richard Bolling (photo of painting) [photo 107] n.d.
    - Prof. Henry C. Brock [photo 108] [1893]
  - Identified portraits, C, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 81-4)
    - K. H. C. [woman] [photo 109] 1905
    - Charles V. Carrington [photo 110] 1900
    - Ella Belle Candy [photo 111] 1896
    - Rose H. Candy [photo 112] 1896
    - Elizabeth Landon Carter (photo of painting) [photo 113] n.d.
    - Robert "King" Carter (photos of paintings) [photos 114-115] n.d.
    - Henry Cohn [photo 116] n.d.
    - Col. E. D. Cole [photo 117] n.d.
    - H. A. [Conners?] [photo 118] [1893]
  - Identified portraits, D-G (Box-folder 81-5)
    - Kent Hairston Draper and father [photo 119] n.d.
    - Louise Eggleston [photo 120] n.d.
    - [Frederick V. Gantt] in V.P.I. cadet uniform [photos 121-122] [1904]
    - Col. William A. Gile [photo 123] n.d.
    - Barbara Haxall Grundy [photo 124] 1934
  - Identified portraits, H (Box-folder 81-6)
    - [Richard?] Hammet [photo 125] n.d.
    - Willis Harmon [photo 126] n.d.
    - Benjamin Harrison (photos of paintings) [photos 127-128] n.d., [2 copies of each]
    - William Henry Harrison (photos of paintings) [photos 129-130] n.d.
    - William Henry Harrison (lithograph) [photo 131] n.d.
    - [?] Hereford in V.M.I. cadet uniform [photo 132] n.d.
    - B. Lacy Hoge [photo 133] n.d.
  - Identified portraits, I-L (Box-folder 81-7)
    - R. R. Jones [photo 134] [1893]
    - Gwenthleen Hoge Kaine [photo 135] n.d.
    - Chas Kane [photo 136] n.d.
    - Mary Guy Brawley King [photo 137] n.d.
    - E. E. Lane [photo 138] [1893]
    - T. A. Lewis [photo 139] [1893]
  - Identified portraits, Ma-Mh (Box-folder 81-8)
    - Suzanne Goldsborough Martin [photo 140] n.d.
    - W. Hammet Martin [photo 141] 1900
    - Mr. Martin [photo 142] n.d.
    - Jno. M. McCoy and Laura G. Taggart [photo 143] n.d.
    - C. W. McDonald [photo 144] [1893]
    - Dr. Richard McIlwaine [photo 145] [1893]
    - Daughter of Duncan McIntyre [photo 146] n.d.
    - Lorenz J. McIntyre [photos 147-148] 1891, n.d.
    - H. W. McLaughlin [photo 149] 1893
    - D. T. Merritt [photo 150] [1893]
  - Identified portraits, Mi-Mz (Box-folder 81-9)
    - Agnes Erskine Miller [photo 151] n.d.
    - [?] Washington Miller [photo 152] n.d.
    - Kate Valentine Montague [photos 153-154] 1898, n.d.
    - [Kate Valentine Montague] [photo 155] n.d.
    - Dr. W. W. Moore [photo 156] [1893]
    - S. B. Morton [photo 157] [1893]
  - Identified portraits, N-R (Box-folder 82-1)
    - E. A. Nickerson [photo 158] n.d.
    - Dr. C. A. Perkins [photo 159] [1893]
    - G. W. Peyton [photo 160] [1893]
    - Pocahontas (photos of paintings) [photos 161-162] n.d.
    - R. B. Preston [photos 163] n.d.
    - John Harris Ramsey [photo 164] n.d.
    - [J.?] Robertson [photo 165] [1893]
    - D. H. Rolston [photo 166] 1893
  - Identified portraits, S (Box-folder 82-2)
    - G. S. Shackleford [photo 167] n.d.
    - Tyler Smith [photo 168] n.d.
    - Prof. William Sommerville [photo 169] [1893]
    - D. Spottswood [photo 170] [1893]
    - L. D. Starke Jr. [photos 171-172] n.d.
    - Joseph Stebbins Jr. [photo 173] 1893
  - Identified portraits, T-Z (Box-folder 82-3)
    - Carter Tyler [photo 174] 1899
    - Evie Tyler [photo 175] n.d.
    - H. C. Tyler [photo 176] n.d.
    - Sue Hammet Tyler (born c.1914) [photo 177] 1916
    - [Sue Hammet Tyler (born 1845)] [photo 178] n.d., [2 copies]
    - Anne Rebecca Radford Wharton [photo 179] 1895
    - R. D. White [photo 180] [1893]
    - J. W. Wool [photo 181] 1893
  - Studio portraits of unidentified men [photos 182-217] n.d., [see also Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 82-4-7)
  - Studio portraits of unidentified women [photos 218-245] n.d., [see also Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 83-1-2)
  - Studio portraits of unidentified children [photos 246-257] (Box-folder 83-3)
  - Portraits of unidentified groups [photos 258-265] n.d. (Box-folder 83-4)
  - Snapshots
    - Identified individuals (Box-folder 83-5)
      - Janet G. Cameron [photo 266] n.d.
      - Dr. M. D. Hoge [photo 267] n.d.
      - Mrs. Thomas N. Jones [photo 268] 1900
      - Chas. A. Magill, grand marshal of Great Civic Parade - Galveston Cotton Carnival [photo 269] 1911
      - Eugenie Moore [photo 270] 1901
      - Eleanor Steinert [photo 271] 1944
      - Roger Wolcott leading Dewey parade [photo 272] 1899
    - Joan Appleton and others at beach [photos 273-280] n.d. (Box-folder 83-6)
    - Unidentified group of women on city sidewalk and in carriage [photos 281-289] n.d. (Box-folder 83-7)
    - Two unidentified men traveling mountain roads of eastern Tennessee [photos 290-293] n.d. (Box-folder 83-8)
    - Unidentified man and two women in snow-covered field [photos 294-299] n.d. (Box-folder 83-8)
    - Unidentified men on the University of Virginia campus [photos 300-305] n.d. (Box-folder 83-9)
    - Unidentified soldiers [photos 306-315] n.d. (Box-folder 83-9)
    - Unidentified pair of women in field with rifle [photos 316-319] n.d. (Box-folder 83-10)
    - Unidentified pair of women posing on stone in field [photos 320-322] n.d. (Box-folder 83-10)
    - Unidentified group of women wearing hats [photos 323-325] n.d. (Box-folder 83-10)
    - Miscellaneous unidentified men [photos 326-342] n.d. (Box-folder 83-11)
    - Miscellaneous unidentified women [photos 343-368] n.d. (Box-folder 83-12-13)
    - Miscellaneous unidentified children [photos 369-389] n.d. (Box-folder 84-1)
    - Miscellaneous unidentified groups [photos 390-428] n.d., [see also Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 84-2-5)
  - Buildings and scenery, A-B (Box-folder 84-6)
    - Achnacarry [photo 429] n.d.
    - Belmont Farm (Keswick, Virginia) [photo 430] n.d.
    - Berkley Plantation (James River, Virginia) wheat harvest [photo 431] n.d.
    - Bonbrook - Wilson home [photos 432-437] 1926
    - Brompton (near Fredericksburg, Virginia) [photo 438] n.d.
  - Buildings and scenery, C-G (Box-folder 84-7)
    - City Hall (Richmond, Virginia) [photo 439] 1900
    - Executive Mansion (Richmond, Virginia) [photos 440-444] 1900
  - Buildings and scenery, H-O, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 84-8)
    - Halwick (Radford, Virginia) [photos 445-451] n.d.
    - Lochiel (Gordonsville, Virginia) [photo 452] n.d.
    - Old Capitol (Richmond, Virginia) (photo of sketch) [photo 453] n.d.
  - Buildings and scenery (Box-folder 84-9)
    - [Pennsboro, West Virginia] [photo 454] n.d.
    - Peyton Randolph House (Williamsburg, Virginia) [photo 455] n.d.
    - Prospect Hill (Berkeley County, West Virginia) [photo 456] 1928
    - Statue of Liberty [photo 457] 1930
    - Sweet Briar College campus [photos 458-463] n.d.
  - Buildings and scenery, T-Z (Box-folder 84-10)
    - Varina (on James River, Virginia) [photo 464] n.d.
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute campus [photos 465-466] n.d.
    - Warren House at Smith's Fort (Surry County, Virginia) [photo 467] n.d.
    - Washington Monument (Richmond, Virginia) [photo 468] 1900
    - YMCA (Radford, Virginia) Christmas dinner setting [photo 469] 1892
  - Miscellaneous buildings and scenery [photos 470-496] n.d. (Box-folder 84-11-12)
  - Animals [photos 497-509] n.d. (Box-folder 84-13)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS (Box 85)
  - Broadsides (from Series I, Subseries VII)
    - "Southwest's choice... Major James Hoge Tyler" 1893
    - "Vote for Todd and Martin: the straight ticket" n.d.
    - "A Hot campaign... Maj. J. Hoge Tyler, Democratic candidate for lieut.-governor, will speak in Berryville, Va...." 1889
  - Virginia Board of Public Works, Statement showing the assessed value of railroad and canal property and the tax extended thereon, in the Commonwealth of Virginia, for the year...1900, (from Series I, Subseries VII)
  - Extradition certificate for Asaph Cole 1898, (from Sereies I, Subseries VIII)
  - Printed materials (from Series II, Subseries VI)
    - Goodson Gazette (Published by the Virginia School for the Deaf and the Blind) Feb 15 1899
    - Radford Oct 1888
    - The Radford News Jan 8 1925
  - Radford Development Company records (from Series III, Subseries I)
    - Stock book 1890-1892
    - Deed book 1890-1891, [also contains county voter contact lists for 1899 campaign]
  - Edward Hammet Papers (from Series XI, Subseries II)
    - Land grant to John Havens Jr. for property on Plum Creek (Montgomery County, Virginia) 1845
    - Land grant to John Pepper for property on Plum Creek (Montgomery County, Virginia) 1840
  - Photographs (from Series XIII)
    - James Hoge Tyler studio portrait (mat inscribed to daughter Lily) n.d.
    - James H. and Lily Tyler studio portrait c.1899
    - Hal C. Tyler 1933, [3 items]
    - [H. Clay?] Cameron n.d.
    - Unidentified man 1937
    - Unidentified man n.d.
    - Unidentified woman n.d.
    - Unidentified football team n.d.
    - Unidentified large group on church steps (Huntington, West Virginia?) n.d.
    - Guests of Applachian Power Company - inspection trip to hydro-electric developments (Byllesby and Grayson, Virginia) 1912
    - Banquet of the Association of Pennsylvania Highway Contractors 1922
    - Manufacturer's and Associated General Contractors of America 1922
    - Old Opequon Church and Graveyard n.d., [2 items]